Hello everyone, [music] and welcome to
Expense Agent series.
I will now show you a little bit about
our approval process in the Expense
Agent.
So, um I am now in my Business Central
environment, and as you can see, I have
already the Expense Agent turned on.
So, the first step is when you turn on
the Expense Agent, or also later on if
you want to change your settings, you
can go in and you can choose a default
approver.
So, this is going to be the person that
is able to approve the expenses for
everyone in your company by default. You
can still change person by person. I'm
going to show that to you in a second.
And this is also not mandatory. So, in
case your company doesn't really have a
default approver, you don't need to set
that up.
Um however, in my case, Alexander is my
default approver, as I showed.
But, if I go into expense users, now I
pinned it to my role center, but you can
also just search for the page. You can
see that uh for everyone in my company,
it's Alexander who is the approver,
except for me. I am Enrico, so here my
approver is Monica. And you can change
that, of course, from the card page for
the expense user. As you can see here to
the right, you can pick a different
expense um user to be an approver.
Notice that there is a flag here called
"Can Approve". That's what controls
which users can be approvals for others.
So, um
make sure that the users I mean, the
system is going to basically make sure
that the person you choose as an
approver is also someone that can
actually approve in the system.
Let's now move to the Expense Agent web
app UI.
So, here, as you can see, we are logged
in with my user.
And I have a couple of expenses that I
have uh uploaded and the system
processed and um assigned and got ready.
So, let's for example pick the first
one.
I can check, of course, that the agent
did everything correctly. In my case,
let's say I checked already um
the attachments and that all the
information is correct.
So, now I can just click submit.
So, now what the system will do is it
will to out from Business Central who is
my approver, and the it will send my
approver an email if I have configured
an email address inside Business
Central.
So, in this case, as you saw earlier, my
approver is Monica. So, Monica is going
to get an email, and I will be in CC to
that email saying that she needs to
approve
some expense reports. So, let's go now
and change the view, and let's see how
Monica sees
the world.
So, now we are in Monica's email box,
and as you can see, we just got a new
email,
which notifies Monica that she has an
expense report that needs her review.
So, now Monica can click on the link.
She can have a look at the high-level
description of the expense report, but
she can also click on review report down
here.
And that will open the
web app view, specifically zoomed in to
the report, of course, that she needs to
act on.
So, Monica can now have a look, and for
example,
open the expenses, and check that
everything looks fine.
So, she can, of course, zoom into the
the receipts that were attached to the
report, and then jump from one to the
other, make sure everything looks okay.
And then, when Monica is happy, she can
approve or send back the receipt
depending on um
yeah, if there's something that needs to
be changed.
In this case, let's say, for example,
that my company has a policy where
when there is a partner visit, the
expense needs to contain the
the partner name, for example, in the
um in the report description.
So, please include um
Please include partner name in report
description. So, now Monica can, for
example, in this case, send this one
back to me, and I will be able to
correct whatever Monica has left as a
comment, and then decide to
um yeah, submit it again when it's
ready.
I have also here as Monica, I have a
second expense report that was submitted
to me and that I haven't approved.
So that let's say that instead, just to
make a different example, I have a look
at this and this looks all good.
And let's say that I have no comment on
this, then I can of course just approve.
And when I approve something then that
will be marked as approved in Business
Central and the process can continue
with posting, with reimbursement and
everything else that needs to be done
after the approval process.
I would like to mention that to set a
person as an approver, so in this case
Monica,
you the approver needs to have a
Business Central license and be a user
in Business Central. Notice that this is
not a requirement for me to submit
expenses. So I could submit even if I
was not a user in Business Central.
Whereas Monica, to be able to approve,
needs to be in the system in Business
Central as a user, as a licensed user to
be specific.
Let's now switch back to my view.
So this is the
Expense Agent web app as I see it. And
as you can see here we have the the
report that Monica sent back with the
comments that Monica left, please
include partner name.
So I can just basically review again
this expense report and I can change the
title. For example, I can say Contoso
Partner Conference.
I can save my changes and now I can
submit it again for Monica to review.
Also, small teaser here. Notice that you
might say
that your companies have policies
written down to have this
fixed. There might be something coming
soon about policies, so stay tuned for
new Expense Agent changes.
As you can see I've been a little bit
lazy, so I have actually an old expense
from November 2025 that I have not
submitted.
Well, Expense Agent gives you the option
as an administrator that sets up the
agent to set up reminders for users that
have not submitted their reports.
So, let's switch back to Business
Central for a second.
And if I go back to
the expense agent setup,
you can see this option to notify users
about unsubmitted reports. So, when you
set up the agent or also later if you
want to change this option, you can
choose a frequency to remind users to
submit their reports.
And this is going to send them an email
with the notification frequency that you
pick.
And the email you receive is going to
look like this. So, this is an example I
have from a few days ago
um where I had some open expense reports
that were ready to submit and I've left
there
um
uncompleted. And as you can see, the
agent reminds me that I should probably
act on these expenses soon.
One last thing I want to mention is that
um as you can see, our current approval
setup is a little bit um basic as in
like you can set up, of course, uh
approver for everyone in your company
and then you can change it for the
single users um if you need to. And um
we know that this is just like the basic
needs for you, but um
just as a small teaser, we have some
more improvements coming for the
approvals in uh expense agent. So, stay
tuned and um for the next wave of
improvements for the expense agent.
Thank you for watching.